# **Jonathan Wheway**

9 Lancaster Road, Bristol, BS29UP, 07841193615, Jonwhewaycode@outlook.com

Formerly from a background in primary engineering, I retrained as a web developer, bringing with me a love of problem-solving, strong attention to detail and a focus on UX.

Throughout my career, I have worked in highly skilled roles that involved interacting with the public and colleagues to find practical solutions to technical problems. My career change was prompted by discovering a love for writing code to benefit my own projects working with microcontrollers and automation.

I am a highly focused and driven individual who is used to working independently, however, I enjoy collaborative working and the opportunity to learn from others. I am a quick learner and always on the lookout for a new challenge, whether it be in coding, electronics or attempting to cultivate veg on my allotment.

Please visit my website click here

Or my GitHub click here

## **Key Skills**

- Web development, Html5, Css3, Javascript, jQuery, C++, Python3, Flask, Django, Mongodb and Mysql.
- Currently up skilling with React.js and PHP.
- Diagnosis and fault finding of sound electronics, audio equipment and coin-operated machinery.
- Fast learner.
- Developing bespoke audio and visual systems.
- Able to work on my own or as part of a team.
- Stock control.

# **Employment**

**SLX hire** Freelance Theatre Technician February 2018 – current

### **Responsibilities:**

• Fault finding and repair of top-line theatre equipment (Including digital moving head lighting, led par cans, audio equipment, stage rigging and high intensity power distribution.

**Wogan Coffee** Mobile Service Engineer June 2018 – February 2019

### **Responsibilities:**

- Fault finding and repair of Espresso machines, Coffee Grinders, Water Boilers.
- Installation Of new and used machinery.

**JNC Sales** Workshop Engineer October 2014 – June 2018

### **Responsibilities:**

- Fault finding and restoration coin operated equipment (Including Fruit machines, Reel based and digital, Juke boxes; CD and Digital, Trivia machines, Children's rides and pushers).
- Graphic design production for advertising materials such as brochures and adverts, brand and machinery logo production.
- Proofing of vinyl printing and cutting products.
- Supervision and training of new workshop staff.
- Customer liaison, providing face to face and phone advice and technical support.
- Support the maintenance of the workshop and workshop equipment.

## **Education**

## 2020-Present - CodeInstitute

Full-stack Software Development
Diploma in Full stack software development

• Tech Fundamentals Diploma in Tech Fundamentals

<u>1998-2000 – Bridgwater College</u>

City & Guilds Parts 1 & 2 in Sound Engineering
Pass \* (highest grade)

1993-1998 – Edington & Shapwick School

GCSEs in English Language, English Literature, Mathematics, Double Science, Information Technology, Design Technology, and French

## Interests

I am a naturally inquisitive person who takes an interest in how the world works. I enjoy working with and developing computer systems and programming. At home I enjoy both creating and building my own electronic systems for a variety of communications and music devices. As well as getting my hands dirty with my hydroponics and my allotment growing food throughout the year or supporting my 5 colonies of bees.

## **Voluntary Work**

### East Bristol Hops Community Project.

Mid-September 2020, I took the administration of a community project called East Bristol Hops Growers Association.

A collective of over 100 people, who grow hops at home, either in pots or in the ground, in their gardens or allotments, balconies etc. A local Bristol brewery then turns the hops into a fantastic tasting beer. My position, is to keep the database of growers up to date, organise events such as socials, hops collection, grower's end of season party, public speaking at the events etc. Since taking on the position, I have created a website, reignited interest in the social media outlets, started creating merchandise to push the brand and bring in needed funds, liaised with local news sources to cover our events and to bring interest to the project.

http://www.eastbristolhops.co.uk